<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on MarceStarlet</title>
    <link>https://marcestarlet.github.io/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on MarceStarlet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marcestarlet.github.io/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Techwo Blog Project</title>
      <link>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/techwo-blog-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/techwo-blog-project/</guid>
      <description>For about 3 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in a women in tech community that has the objective to increase the number of women participating in technology, and trying to achive this main objective I got the idea to start a blog project that gathers some of the brightest women I know as writers of this blog and that for a year will write a post about technology every week.
I know most of those selected women for this project and the others that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been starting to see their talent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be A Programmer In The Near Future</title>
      <link>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/be-a-programmer-in-the-near-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/be-a-programmer-in-the-near-future/</guid>
      <description>Now a days I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that EVERYBODY must know how to program, due the technology is everywhere, due your abilities and skills will be developed in a creative way.
I think all of these arguments are valid and I really agreed them, but I believe that be a programmer is now more than just know how to program. If everybody learn how to program, I don&amp;rsquo;t think all become into programmers, the evolution of the software is turning the meaning into a more complex and complete definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT - Concepts &amp; Usage</title>
      <link>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/mqtt-concepts-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/mqtt-concepts-usage/</guid>
      <description>MQTT - Concepts &amp;amp; Usage The last part of this serie of posts about MQTT will cover some concepts about the protocol that essentialy will show us the boundaries of the protocol and how it handles the connections between clients and the broker.
Connection Let&amp;rsquo;s start by defining the MQTT Connection. The connection initiates when a client sends a CONNECT message to the broker, then the broker responds with a CONNACK and a status code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT - The Protocol</title>
      <link>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/mqtt-the-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/mqtt-the-protocol/</guid>
      <description>MQTT - The protocol Now that you know the reason of the existence of MQTT and where to use it, you can learn how it works and then how to use it.
 My philosophy: Only when we know the reason of why a technology exists and where we can apply it, the technology becomes real, otherwise does not exists.
 Now some context, take it from Wikipedia the definition of protocol: In telecommunications, a communications protocol is a system of rules that allow two or more entities of a communications system to transmit information via any kind of variation of a physical quantity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/mqtt-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/mqtt-introduction/</guid>
      <description>INTRODUCTION What about MQTT? Have you heard about MQTT? Hope you have, but if you haven&amp;rsquo;t, don&amp;rsquo;t worry you&amp;rsquo;ll be hearing more about it in the next months since it&amp;rsquo;s becoming popular.
MQTT is the most popular protocol used for IoT (internet of things) but don&amp;rsquo;t get confused, MQTT isn&amp;rsquo;t only for IoT, as it is a protocol it can be used in most of the communication situations, like TCP/IP does, but there are some great things that becomes MQTT special and unique to solve a communication problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome 2016</title>
      <link>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/welcome-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://marcestarlet.github.io/p/welcome-2016/</guid>
      <description>El comienzo/The begining Hola/Hi
Mi nombre es Marcela Sena conocida como MarceStarlet, tengo 28 años, soy Ingeniero de Software y vivo en Guadalajara, Jal., México; les doy la bienvenida a éste mi nuevo blog de programación/conceptos/tecnologías/herramientas/tendencias/ciencias computacionales/etc., esperando sea de su agrado.
La idea de este blog es compartirles lo que sé, lo que estoy aprendiendo, y lo que me gustaría aprender, todo relacionado con las ciencias computacionales. El reto para mi es escribirles frecuentemente; al menos una vez al mes encontrarán un post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
