<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Skills on MarceStarlet</title>
    <link>http://marcestarlet.github.io/tags/skills/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Skills on MarceStarlet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>cosmo.marce &lt;at&gt; gmail &lt;dot&gt; com (Marcela Sena)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>cosmo.marce &lt;at&gt; gmail &lt;dot&gt; com (Marcela Sena)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 15:08:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://marcestarlet.github.io/tags/skills/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>TechWo Blog project</title>
            <link>http://marcestarlet.github.io/blog/2017/04/27/techwo-blog-project/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 15:08:10 -0500</pubDate>
            <author>cosmo.marce &lt;at&gt; gmail &lt;dot&gt; com (Marcela Sena)</author>
            <guid>http://marcestarlet.github.io/blog/2017/04/27/techwo-blog-project/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://marcestarlet.github.io/img/TechWoBlog.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;alt&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For about 3 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in a women in tech community that has the
objective to increase the number of women participating in technology, and trying
to achive this main objective I got the idea to start a blog project that gathers
some of the brightest women I know as writers of this blog and that for a year
will write a post about technology every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know most of those selected women for this project and the others that I didn&amp;rsquo;t
know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been starting to see their talent. One of my favorite part of this project
is that each one of the woman that are participating are really sharing what they
know, what they like or even what they are implementing on their jobs, and I can
noticed that each of them are growing on each of their career paths as well as they
learn more about themselves. The other thing I love is how we have been created
a real community improving all the posts written until now, because we&amp;rsquo;re not only
writers, we&amp;rsquo;re also reviewers and we do comments to improve the redaction of every
post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is the most wonderful project that I&amp;rsquo;ve started with the organizer women
in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techwo.org/&#34;&gt;TechWo&lt;/a&gt; because this is the first time I think I&amp;rsquo;m doing the difference for the
women that I want to motivate that are the programmers. TechWo is for every women
involved in technology not only for programmers, but my expertise area in thechnology
is programming and all related to software development, that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m so interested
in share my knowledge trying to motivate other girls to do and love this amazing
career that I think gives a lot for a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the posts of the blog are written in spanish since that is our native language
and because the blog is focused to the spanish-speaking community, we want to give
power to the &amp;ldquo;Hispano&amp;rdquo; community due many of the articles, books, tutorials and Internet
contet about technology is written in english, so we want to get close to those people
that have not the chance to get in contact or learn english.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to invite you to see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.techwomen.org.mx/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt; and let us your comments if you like, you have doubts
or you want to improve the content. Besides to invite you to visit and read the blog
I also want to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ll been adding here a short description in english of
the posts I write, due I know they could be of your interest, it is possible that you could
be also interested in learn spanish :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>Be a programmer in the near future</title>
            <link>http://marcestarlet.github.io/blog/2016/10/31/be-a-programmer-in-the-near-future/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 15:17:30 -0500</pubDate>
            <author>cosmo.marce &lt;at&gt; gmail &lt;dot&gt; com (Marcela Sena)</author>
            <guid>http://marcestarlet.github.io/blog/2016/10/31/be-a-programmer-in-the-near-future/</guid>
            <description>

&lt;p&gt;Now a days I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that &lt;em&gt;EVERYBODY&lt;/em&gt; must know how to program, due the technology is
everywhere, due your abilities and skills will be developed in a creative way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think all of these arguments are valid and I really agreed them, but I believe
that be a programmer is now more than just know how to program. If everybody learn
how to program, I don&amp;rsquo;t think all become into programmers, the evolution of the software
is turning the meaning into a more complex and complete definition.
The idea to teach the kids about programming is &lt;em&gt;in mi humble opinion&lt;/em&gt;,
to let them know other way to solve problems using technology, prepare the minds of
the new generations with the &lt;em&gt;civic&lt;/em&gt; knowledge about how to improve the
world, and for obvious reasons they won&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to get in touch with technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a few words:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;use the technology in your favor and in the others favor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if everybody will know how to program, but no all will become into programmers &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-the-hell-will-be-a-programmer&#34;&gt;Who the hell will be a programmer?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many definitions to describe what a programmer is, and the opinion of
every programmer will be different so, I&amp;rsquo;m going to mention the things I believe
are the most common and also I&amp;rsquo;m going to add mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, a programmer is a person who writes software, who use a programming
language to develop &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;professional&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; programs that solve problems or improve manual process.
I did emphasis in the word professional because I believed this will be the differentiator
between who will know how to program and who will be a programmer. When the people change their
code from &amp;ldquo;garage code&amp;rdquo; into a &amp;ldquo;professional code&amp;rdquo;, the programmer inside them, will have born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For professional, I mean that their code will have the following characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll be complete

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely functional (it works)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usable and useful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will accomplish the requirement(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will solve the problem in the better way (relative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will follow the best practices of the language in which it was written&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will be tested (at least unit test)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The code will be documented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The code will be maintainable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will be collaborative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible that they, will just write a few lines of code at the begining, but it won&amp;rsquo;t matter
the number of lines, what will really matter, is that those lines will be well written since
the beginning, because their formation as a programmer will tell them, that they do not only
know how to program, it will tell them that they know the best way of how to program, or the best
way of write code to do it professional and collaborative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many opinios of how a programmer should be, this my opinion of the near future of
the programmers and how I believe this profesion will turn into.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          </item>
        
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
